A call option allows
an investor to pay a fixed
premium for the right,
but not the obligation,
to buy an asset at
a predetermined price
until expiration.
The long call strategy might be
useful for an investor who is
bullish on either the markets
or the price of a specific stock.
Investors going long
calls make profits if
the price of the
underlying shares rise
above the combined value of
the strike price and the
net cost of the option.
The payoff from a long call
position is unlimited,
increasing point for
point with the stock
if the price of the underlying
shares moves higher.
The loss potential is limited
to the initial cost
of the option.
Investors face a maximum
loss of the premium
and any point at or
below the strike price,
above which point
losses diminish.
The value of a long call option
is hurt by the passage of
time and benefits from
increases in volatility.